skillpages.com 2014-12-26

# Privacy Policy - SkillPages

* ## INFORMATION THAT WE COLLECT AND HOW WE USE IT

  1. We collect information on Users in order to facilitate the operation of the SkillPages Platform.
  2. The User consents and knowingly chooses to disclose all information that is uploaded to the SkillPages Platform in the form of a SkillPage. When you add to your SkillPage with further information about yourself, you agree that any registration information you give to SkillPages will always be accurate, correct and up to date.
  3. The SkillPages Search Facility is available to all Users. Users are also invited to enter personal information which provides an enhanced set of search results. 
    1. When you sign up for a SkillPages Account (or 'SkillPage') or other SkillPages services or promotions that require registration, we ask you for personal information such as name, geo-location and email address. After you have created your SkillPage we provide you with the option to add additional personal information such as phone number. We may combine the information that you submit under your SkillPage with information from other SkillPages, in order to provide you with a better experience and to improve the quality of our services or to suggest to you people you might know, or other people who may have skills of interest to you. For certain information, we give you the opportunity to opt out of combining such information within your account settings page.
    2. SkillPages provides an invitation service when you register with the Platform. If you choose (consent or opt in) to use our invitation service to tell a contact about our site, we will ask you for information needed to send the invitation, such as your contact’s email address or we will ask you to consent to having your contact list(s) imported. We will send your contacts an email in your name inviting him or her to visit the site, and we will send additional reminders. SkillPages stores this information to send invitations and reminders, to register a contact connection if your invitation is accepted, to allow you to see invitations you have sent and to track the success of our referral program. Your friend may contact us at [help@skillpagessupport.com](mailto:help@skillpagessupport.com), to request that we remove this information from our database.  
All information that you enter or upload about your contacts will be covered by the same terms of this privacy policy as cover your own information.  
You can import contacts from your Outlook or other email account address book to invite them to become members of our site. We collect the username and password for the email account you wish to import your contacts from and will only use it for that purpose. SkillPages also stores this information (imported contacts information) to avoid duplication of contacts and to check when contacts, not invited by the User, join the SkillPages Platform through registration. SkillPages will also store the User’s access details in order to synch the contacts whenever the User logs in.
    3. When you visit SkillPages, we use a third party tracking partner to gather certain information automatically and store it in log files. This information includes internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp and clickstream data. We use this information, which does not identify individual users, to analyze trends, to administer the site, to track users’ movements around the site and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole.
    4. In addition, we store certain information from your browser using 'cookies'. For more information about how we use cookies, please refer to the [SkillPages cookie policy](http://www.skillpages.com/cookies).
    5. When you use SkillPages, you may set up your SkillPage, form community networks, send messages, perform searches and queries, set up events, add applications, transmit information through various channels and send emails or other communications to SkillPages. We collect the personal information as outlined above so that we can provide you the service and offer personalized features. In most cases, we retain it so that, for instance, you can return to view prior messages you have sent or easily see your community network list.
    6. When you post User Content on the Site in areas such as blogs and forums, you do so at your own risk. We cannot and do not guarantee that User Content you post on the Site will not be viewed by unauthorized persons. We are not responsible for circumvention of any settings or security measures contained on the Site. You understand and acknowledge that, even after removal, copies of User Content may remain viewable in cached and archived pages or if other Users have copied or stored your User Content. To request removal of your personal information from our blog or community forum, contact us at {0}. In some cases, we may not be able to remove your personal information, in which case we will let you know if we are unable to do so and why.
    7. SkillPages have the right to reformat and move SkillPages, and SkillPage information. SkillPages reserve the right to remove, edit the look and feel of, move or close any SkillPage for any reason and to suspend or ban any User Account for any reason.
  4. Any improper collection or misuse of information provided on SkillPages is a violation of the SkillPages Terms and Conditions of Use.
  5. SkillPages only processes personal information for the purposes described in this Privacy Policy. In addition to the above, such purposes include: 
    1. Providing our services, primarily making SkillPages available to all;
    2. Providing more relevant search results by utilizing data provided by the User;
    3. Auditing, research and analysis in order to maintain, protect and improve our services;
    4. Ensuring the technical functioning of SkillPages;
    5. Protecting the rights or property of SkillPages or our Users; and
    6. Developing new services.
  6. By using SkillPages, you are consenting to have your personal data transferred to and processed in such jurisdictions as is necessary.
  7. We provide you the opportunity to participate in surveys on our site. If you participate, we will link certain personally identifiable information provided when you registered for the site to you. Participation in these surveys is completely voluntary and you therefore have a choice whether or not to disclose this information. We use this information to gauge the level of user satisfaction with the site. We use a third party service provider to conduct these surveys. That company is prohibited from using our users’ personally identifiable information for any other purpose. We will not share the personally identifiable information you provide through a survey with other third parties unless we give you prior notice and choice.

* ## USE OF INFORMATION OBTAINED BY SKILLPAGES

  1. When you register with SkillPages, you create your own SkillPage. We may use your name and email address to send you notifications. If you no longer wish to receive these email communications, you may unsubscribe by following the instruction contained in each of the emails you receive.
  2. SkillPage information is used by SkillPages primarily to be presented back to and edited by you when you access the service and to be presented to all.
  3. The SkillPage information that you submit to SkillPages (including phone numbers) will be available to all Users of the SkillPages Platform (whether the user is or is not a registered member of the SkillPages platform). All SkillPage information will be available in search results generated for Users and may be made available to third-party search engines. If you no longer wish to have your information indexed you have the option of deleting your Account. People that see your name in searches will be able to access your SkillPage information without registering with the SkillPages Platform. If you do not want to be listed in our directory you have the option of deleting your Account.
  4. SkillPage information is used by SkillPages to improve the functionality of the SkillPages Platform.
  5. SkillPages may send you service-related announcements from time to time through the general operation of the service.
  6. SkillPages reserves the right to send you notices about your Account even if you opt out of all voluntary email notifications.
  7. SkillPages may use information in your SkillPage without identifying you as an individual to third parties. We do this for purposes such as aggregating how many people are in a network like a group of electricians, and also personalizing advertisements and promotions so that we can provide you with up to date SkillPages promotions and sponsors of community groupings. We believe this benefits you. Where such information is used, we generally allow you to specify in your User Account Settings that you do not want this to be done or to take other actions that limit the connection of this information to your SkillPage (e.g. removing photo tag links).
  8. We post customer testimonials on our web site which may contain personally identifiable information. We do obtain the user consent via email prior to posting the testimonial to post their name along with their testimonial. If you wish to request the removal of your testimonial, you may contact us at [help@skillpagessupport.com](mailto:help@skillpagessupport.com).
  9. If you wish to subscribe to our newsletter(s), we will use your email address to send the newsletter to you. Out of respect for your privacy, you may choose to stop receiving our newsletter or marketing emails by following the unsubscribe instructions included in these emails, accessing the email preferences in your account settings page or you can contact us at [help@skillpagessupport.com](mailto:help@skillpagessupport.com).
  10. Our Web site offers publicly accessible blogs. You should be aware that any information you provide in this area may be read, collected, and used by others who access them. You can request the removal of your personal information from our blog, by contacting us at [help@skillpagessupport.com](mailto:help@skillpagessupport.com). In some cases, we may not be able to remove your personal information, in which case we will let you know if we are unable to do so and why.
  11. Single Sign-On You can log in to our site using sign-in services such as Facebook Connect or an Open ID provider. These services will authenticate your identity and provide you the option to share certain personal information with us such as your name and email address to pre-populate our sign up form. Services like Facebook Connect give you the option to post information about your activities on this Web site to your profile page to share with others within your network. 
  12. Our Web site includes Social Media Features, such as the Facebook Like button and Widgets, such as the Share this button or interactive mini-programs that run on our site. These Features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our site, and may set a cookie to enable the Feature to function properly. Social Media Features and Widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our Site. Your interactions with these Features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it. 

* ## CHILDREN AGED UNDER 14

SkillPages does not knowingly collect or solicit personal information from anyone under the age of 14 or knowingly allow such persons to register. If you are under 14, please do not attempt to register for SkillPages or send any personal information about yourself to us (including your name, address, telephone number or email address). No one under the age of 14 may provide any personal information to SkillPages on the SkillPages Platform. In the event that we learn that we have collected personal information from a child under the age of 14 without verification of parental consent, we will delete that information.

* ## CHILDREN BETWEEN THE AGES OF 14 AND 18

We recommend that children 14 years of age or older ask their parents for permission before sending any information about themselves to anyone over the Internet.

* ## SHARING YOUR INFORMATION WITH THIRD PARTIES

  1. SkillPages is about sharing catalogued skill information with Users. We share your information with third parties only in limited circumstances where we believe such sharing is (1) reasonably necessary to offer the service, (2) legally required or (3) permitted by you.
  2. We may provide information to service providers such as an email service provider to send out emails on our behalf, an author management service to provide you with our blog and a customer support service to gather feedback and assist you with questions to help us bring you the services we offer. Specifically, we may use third parties to facilitate our business. In connection with these offerings and business operations, our service providers may have access to your personal information for use for a limited time in connection with these business activities. Where we utilize third parties for the processing of any personal information, we implement reasonable contractual and technical protections limiting the use of that information to the SkillPages-specified purposes. This site uses various analytics services to monitor and improve the quality and usability of the SkillPages Platform.
  3. We may be required to disclose User information pursuant to lawful requests, such as subpoenas or court orders, or in compliance with applicable laws. We do not reveal information until we have a good faith belief that an information request by law enforcement or private litigants meets applicable legal standards. Additionally, we may share Account or other information when we believe it is necessary to comply with law, to protect our interests or property, to prevent fraud or other illegal activity perpetrated through the SkillPages service or using the SkillPages name, or to prevent imminent bodily harm. This may include sharing information with other companies, lawyers, agents or government agencies.  
If SkillPages becomes involved in a merger, acquisition or any form of sale of some or all of its assets, your personally identifiable information will likely be among the assets transferred. You will be notified via email and/or a prominent notice on our Web site for 30 days of any such change in ownership or control of your personal information.
  4. You can share your SkillPages information with outside applications and websites such as Facebook to make your experiences on those applications and websites better and more commercial.
  5. We are not responsible for any third party applications and websites that you interact with through the SkillPages Platform.
  6. If you log in to SkillPages using one of these application’s or website’s sign-in services and connect with your SkillPages Account, that application or website can access information on SkillPages related to you and your contacts and generate and publish stories about actions you take on that application or website without any additional permission. An application or website that you connect with can generally access the same information that you can see about yourself and your contacts, and an application or website that your contacts connect with can access the same information about you that the contacts can see.
  7. You can report any suspected misuse of the SkillPages Platform to us, and we will investigate the claim and take appropriate action.
  8. All sharing of information is done at your own risk.

* ## LINKS

SkillPages may contain links to other websites. We are not responsible for the privacy practices of other websites. We encourage our Users to be aware when they leave our site that they should read the privacy documents of each and every website that collects personally identifiable information. This Privacy Policy applies solely to information collected by SkillPages.

* ## CHANGING OR REMOVING INFORMATION

Access and control over most personal information on SkillPages is readily available through the settings page. SkillPages Users may modify or delete any of their Account information at any time by logging into their Account. Individuals who wish to delete their SkillPages Account may do so through your User Account Settings. Removed information may persist in back-up copies for a reasonable period of time but will not be generally available to Users of SkillPages. 

We will retain your information for as long as your Account is active or as needed to provide you services. We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes and enforce our agreements. 

If you wish to request the deletion of an unauthorized profile, you may do so by emailing us at [help@skillpagessupport.com](mailto:help@skillpagessupport.com). 

If you wish to update your privacy settings you may do so by going to the User Account Settings tab in your account center after logging into your account.

Where you make use of the communication features of the service to share information with other individuals on SkillPages, however, (e.g. sending a personal message to another SkillPages User) you generally cannot remove such communications. SkillPages reserves the right to remove any data stored on the platform.

* ## ACCESSING AND UPDATING PERSONAL INFORMATION

  1. Deleting your Account. If you delete your Account, Users will not be able to see it but it will not be deleted. When you delete your account however, it is permanently deleted. You will not be able to reinstate your Account and you will have to create a new Account.
  2. Even after you deactivate or delete your Account, you should be aware that copies of the information may remain accessible elsewhere, specifically in relation to the extent that it has been previously shared with others, or if it was copied or stored by other Users.

* ## SECURITY

SkillPages takes appropriate precautions to protect our Users’ information. The security of your personal information is important to us. When you enter sensitive information (such as a credit card number) on our order forms, we encrypt the transmission of that information using secure socket layer technology (SSL). We follow generally accepted standards to protect the personal information submitted to us, both during transmission and once we receive it. Your Account information is located on a secure server behind a firewall. Therefore, we cannot guarantee its absolute security. If you have any questions about security on our Web site, you can contact us at [help@skillpagessupport.com](mailto:help@skillpagessupport.com).

* ## PUBLIC MEMBER DIRECTORY

We will list you in our publicly accessible member directory. If you wish to request removal of your information from our directory, you can contact us at {0}.

* ## PUBLIC PROFILE

The profile you create on our site will be publically accessible unless otherwise indicated. You may change the privacy settings of your profile through your account portal.

* ## TERMS AND CONDITIONS OF USE, NOTICES AND REVISIONS

Your use of SkillPages, and any disputes arising from it, is subject to this Privacy Policy as well as our Terms and Conditions of Use and all of its dispute resolution provisions including limitation on damages and choice of law. We reserve the right to change our Privacy Policy and our Terms and Conditions of Use at any time. Changes and clarifications will take effect immediately upon their posting on this site. If we make material changes to this policy, we will notify you here, by email or through notice on the SkillPages website prior to the changes becoming effective. We encourage you to refer to this policy on an ongoing basis so that you understand our current privacy policy. Unless stated otherwise, our current privacy policy applies to all information that we have about you and your Account.

* ## CHOICES FOR PERSONAL INFORMATION

  1. When you sign up to create an Account, this requires registration and we ask you to provide personal information. If we use this information in a manner different from the purpose for which it was collected, then we will ask for your consent prior to such use.
  2. If we propose to use personal information for any purposes other than those described in this Privacy Policy and/or in the specific service privacy notices, we will offer you an effective way to opt out of the use of personal information for those other purposes. We will not collect or use sensitive information for purposes other than those described in this Privacy Policy and/or in the supplementary service privacy notices, unless we have obtained your prior consent.
  3. Most browsers are initially set up to accept cookies, but you can reset your browser to refuse all cookies or to indicate when a cookie is being sent. However, some SkillPages features and services may not function properly if your cookies are disabled.

* ## DATA INTEGRITY

SkillPages processes personal information only for the purposes for which it was collected and in accordance with this Privacy Policy or any applicable service-specific privacy notice. We review our data collection, storage and processing practices to ensure that we only collect, store and process the personal information needed to provide or improve our services or as otherwise permitted under this Policy. We take reasonable steps to ensure that the personal information that we process is accurate, complete and current, but we depend on our Users to update or correct their personal information whenever necessary.

* ## PRIVACY MATTERS

When we receive formal written or emailed complaints it is SkillPages’s policy to contact the complaining User regarding his or her concerns. We will cooperate with the appropriate regulatory authorities, including local data protection authorities, to resolve any complaints regarding the transfer of personal data that cannot be resolved between SkillPages and an individual.

* ## CONTACT US

If you have any questions or suggestions regarding our privacy policy, please contact us at: [help@skillpagessupport.com](mailto:help@skillpagessupport.com), via postal mail at Block 1 Blackrock Business Park, Blackrock, Co. Dublin, Ireland or by telephone on +353 1 2000 210.
